bov.com 2013-09-09

# Bank of Valletta

In terms of Article 10 of the Data Protection Act 2001, customers who wish to opt out from receiving any type of direct marketing from Bank of Valletta plc should download the appropriate form and send it to the nearest branch. Non-BOV customers should complete the same form and address it to BOV Gozo Operations Centre, Bella Vista Court No2, Gorg Borg Olivier Street, Victoria VCT 2517, Gozo.

** _To view these documents you need Adobe Acrobat Reader®  
(if you don't have it please _[_click here to download and install_](http://www.adobe.com/products/acrobat/readstep2.html) _)_

We have developed this policy because we want you to feel confident about the privacy and security of your personal information. Please read it carefully:

  1. We do not provide any third parties with any information regarding a customer’s financial transactions/accounts unless obliged to do so by law by court order or with your specific consent.
  2. According to law, we may be required from time to time to disclose your information to Governmental bodies, agencies or our Regulators, but we will only do so under proper authority.
  3. We only collect information that we believe to be relevant and required to understand a customer’s present or future financial needs, or the needs of our customers in general, and to conduct our business.
  4. Market research using customer information is only carried out for internal purposes, so that we may understand our customers’ needs and business trends in order to develop and/or improve the products and services that we offer.
  5. It is our policy to send direct marketing material related to our financial products or from carefully selected third parties that may provide products or services to us, or our customers, at preferential rates or conditions. Customers have a right to request not to receive direct marketing material by informing us in writing.
  6. Third party companies/organisations may be contracted to carry out bulk mailing/marketing campaigns on the Bank’s behalf. For this purpose, we will require to provide such companies/organisations with your name, address and other contact details, excluding personal financial information, as part of a mailing list. We will require such companies/organisations to strictly comply with all applicable provisions of law when using the information included in the mailing list.
  7. All reasonable efforts are made to keep customer information up-to-date. Please help us take prompt and efficient action by informing us of any changes to your personal information either by visiting your branch or writing to us. Please write to us if you want to know exactly what personal information we hold on you. If it transpires that the information held is inaccurate, we will make the necessary amendments and confirm to you that these have been made.
  8. We strive to invest in the latest security technologies available and maintain strict information security policies designed to prevent unauthorised access to your information by anyone, including our staff.
  9. All our staff and all authorised third parties (eg support services) with permitted access to your information are specifically required to comply with the Bank’s Information Security Policies.
  10. When using the public portion of the website, you may be required to provide us with your personal information, however this information is only used for the purpose for which it is collected eg to send the requested product information, unless you specifically choose otherwise. If you provide us with your email address, we will treat it just as securely as other personal information. We will not send you unsolicited email messages or junk mail.
  11. Similar to other websites, our website utilises a standard technology called ‘cookies’. Cookies are pieces of information that a website transfers to your computer's hard disc for record keeping, statistical and analysis purposes. They record the number of times people visit certain pages on our website. However, they are not used to access your personal information. They are a tool we use to analyse which web pages people prefer to view, in an aggregated manner. Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies. If you prefer, you can set your browser to refuse cookies. However, given that we may sometimes use cookies, you may not be able to take full advantage of our website if you do so.
  12. Links which we provide to third-party websites are clearly marked and the Bank is not responsible for the content of such websites or their privacy policies.
  13. We may record telephone conversations to offer additional security or resolve complaints.
  14. According to law, all our staff are personally responsible for maintaining customer confidentiality.
  15. As the Internet is an inherently insecure medium of communication, we do not send any customer information via electronic mail even if a customer requests it, unless the appropriate security measures are in place.
  16. Unless otherwise stated in specific terms and conditions of use of any part of our website, we may change the content or services found on our website at any time without notice, and consequently our privacy policy may change at any time in the future.
  17. You agree to revisit this page regularly and your continued access to or use of our website will mean that you agree to any and all changes.
  18. In this policy, “we” and “us” refers to Bank of Valletta plc and its subsidiaries, and “our” shall be construed accordingly.
  19. If you have any questions regarding privacy issues, you may call our Data Protection Officer on telephone (00356) 2275 3024 for more information.
